

→ +1-607-216-5590

huq.irit@gmail.com
GitHub Profile
LinkedIn Profile

ABOUT ME

Recent PhD in mathematics from UC Berkeley interested in taking a more tech-oriented role. Aside from my knowledge of math and physics, I have taken and helped teach many courses in theoretical computer science and operations research. I also have a background in competitive programming, as well as knowledge of various machine learning protocols. I am interested in data science, software engineering, machine learning, artificial intelligence, quantum computing or anything where my knowledge and skills would be relevant.

EDUCATION

| •UC Berkeley PhD in Mathematics, Subject Area: Mathematical Physics | 2017-23 GPA: 4.0 |
|---|---------------------|
| •Columbia University | 2013-2017 |
| BA in Mathematics | GPA: 3.7 |

WORK EXPERIENCE

•UC Berkeley Department of Mathematics

2017 - 2023

 $Research\ Assistant\ +\ Graduate\ Student\ Instructor$

Berkeley, CA

- Conducted research in mathematical physics. Wrote papers and presented at conferences. Assisted for and taught classes in Calculus, Precalculus, and Linear Algebra

•Columbia University Department of Computer Science

2015-2017

 $Undergraduate\ Teaching\ Assistant$

New York, NY

 Assisted for and taught classes in Number Theory and Cryptography, Analysis of Algorithms, and Computational Complexity

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, SQL, HTML

ML Tools:PyToch, Tensorflow, Pandas, Keras, ResNet

Other: LATEX, Mathematica, Canvas, Microsoft Excel

Relevant Coursework: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Computational Complexity, Discrete Optimization, Combinatorial Optimization, Linear Algebra

PERSONAL PROJECTS

•Tree Classification 2023

Erdos Institute Data Science Boot Camp Project

Description: I worked with team of other graduate students and postdocs to use the ReforestTree dataset to train
a model to classify trees from satellite images, and estimate their total carbon storage potential. Details of the
project and its results are available on my GitHub page

Honors and Awards

| •Certificate of Completion Erdos Institute Data Science Bootcamp | 2023 |
|---|-----------|
| •Graduate Student Research Fellowship National Science Foundation | 2018-2023 |
| •Science Research Fellow Columbia University (Award given to fund summer research promising students) | 2013-2017 |
| •2nd Place St.Bonaventure University High School Programming Competition | 2012 |

REFERENCES

Available upon request.